Alex Sheridan

alexsheridan@hotmail.fr 62 Rue du Faubourg Saint-Denis, 75010 Paris +33 (0)6 66 21 84 84

CURRENT POSITION

French Institute for Demographic Studies (INED), Paris, France April 2020 - August 2024 Research assistant for project Sogenre: handling data from the Étude Longitudinale Française depuis l'Enfance (ELFE) and the Millennium Cohort Study (MCS), contributing to the empirical and writing processes, providing logistical support for the project, creating and managing the project's website using INED software. Main collaborators: O. Samuel, C. Brugeilles, Y. Demoli, C. Hamelin, A. Paillet, T. Simeon.

WORK EXPERIENCE

INED. Paris. France

July 2022

Translator for project Guide/EuroCohort: translating pilot questionnaires.

INED, Paris, France

April 2021 - July 2022

Data manager for project DICE: handling data from Direction de l'évaluation, de la prospective et de la performance (DEPP), contributing to the empirical and writing processes, creating and managing the project's website using INED software.

Main collaborators: A. Solaz, L. Panico, T. Schneider, E. Washbrook, J. Waldfogel, R. Keizer.

INED, followed by a contract with the **OECD**, Paris, France

April 2020 - November 2020

Research internship: handling data from Program for International Student Assessment 2018 (PISA), contributing to the empirical process.

Main collaborators: L. Panico, O. Thévenon, L. Berger.

Université Paris Descartes, Paris, France

September 2019 - June 2020

Teaching assistant: Undergraduate macroeconomics classes.

L'AGEFI, Paris, France

Summer of 2019

Journalism internship: Writing about macroeconomic and financial news.

Phefeni Senior Secondary School, Soweto, Johannesburg, South Africa

Summer of 2018

Volunteer teacher as part of the Warwick in Africa charity.

EDUCATION

Paris School of Economics, Paris, France

2018 - 2020

Master's Analysis and Policy in Economics (APE), magna cum laude

Co-accredited by the EHESS, the ENS-PSL, the Ecole des Ponts ParisTech and Université Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne

Master's thesis: "Older siblings and divorce: Evidence from the British Cohort Study," under the supervision of Andrew Clark.

Warwick University, UK (Erasmus programme)

2017 - 2018

Université Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne, Paris, France

2015 - 2018

Undergraduate degree in Economics, magna cum laude

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

Sheridan A., Dräger J., Schneider T., Olczyk M., Solaz A., Washbrook E., Perinetti Casoni V., Kwon S. & Waldfogel J. (In press). "The relevance of tracking and social segregation for growing achievement gaps by parental education in lower secondary school. A longitudinal analysis in France, Germany, the United States, and England." European Sociological Review. Preprint.

MANUSCIPTS UNDER REVIEW

Research article

"Family trajectories, maternal education and achievement gaps: a comparative perspective. Findings on England, France, Germany and the US."

With Jascha Dräger, Thorsten Schneider, Melanie Olczyk, Anne Solaz, Lidia Panico, Elizabeth Washbrook, Valentina Perinetti Casoni, Sarah Kwon & Jane Waldfogel

WORK IN PROGRESS

Research article

"Comparative work on toilet training in France and in the UK: gender and social variations." With Olivia Samuel

Research article

"Parental care during the first year of life: gender and social variations in practices and tastes." With Olivia Samuel, Christine Hamelin & Yoann Demoli

Research article

"Habiller pour genrer? Pratiques sociales autour du vêtement dans la toute petite enfance." With Olivia Samuel, Christine Hamelin & Anne Paillet

OECD Publication & Research article

"The relevance of tracking and social segregation for growing achievement gaps by parental education in lower secondary school. A longitudinal analysis in France, Germany, the United States, and England."

With Lidia Panico, Olivier Thévenon & Lawrence Berger

AWARDS

COORDINATE Transnational Access Visits

October 2023 - November 2023

Three week visit at the Policy Evaluation and Research Unit in Manchester with a £3500 bursary.

PRESENTATIONS

Policy Evaluation and Research Unit lunch seminar, PERU, November 2023. Oral presentation. "Comparative work on toilet training in France and in the UK: gender and social variations."

Children of the noughties: a conference to celebrate 21 years of the Millennium Cohort Study, London, June 2023. Oral presentation. "Parental care during the first year of life: gender and social variations in practices and tastes."

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Co-organiser, Reading group seminar, INED

September 2023 -

Early reasearchers seminar organised around discussion on Schimel, J. (2012). "Writing science: how to write papers that get cited and proposals that get funded." OUP USA.

Student association president, Paris School of Economics

2019 - 2020

Communication officer for the student association, Paris School of Economics

2018 - 2019

LANGUAGES

French: Native
English: Native

Spanish: Needs refreshing but strong basis

PROGRAMMING

LATEX: Overleaf

R: Data cleaning, Descriptive statistics, Econometrics, RMarkdown

Stata: Data cleaning, Descriptive statistics, Econometrics

GitHub: Website development, GitHub profile: alextranslatus